Romualdi, Serafino Papers 5459
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- "D", 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Includes proposed forward for SR's book by David Dubinsky
- "F", 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Corres. with Funk & Wagnall re publication of Presidents and Peons, and with J.V. Freitas Marcondes (Superintendent de Instituto Cultural Do Trabalho) re RS's book and the Institute
- "G", 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  Corres. w/Peter Grace (W.R. Grace & Co.) concerning promotion of Presidents and Peons; also correspondence. w/Arturo Jauregui
- "H", 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  Corres. with William M. Hickey (United Corp.) about his work as Labor Consultant for United Corporation(l966 - 1967); with Robert Hill (former Ambassador) concerning Richard Nixon's support for SR's book (1966) and Nixon's positive comment about RS's anal
- "I", 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  Ibanez to Romualdi re courses of Inter-American Labor College
- "J", 1967 (Box 13, Folder 8a)
  Corres. with Arturo Jauregui re AIFLD meetings; ORIT Conferences; and copies of correspondence. with Jauregui from others
- "K", 1967 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- "L", 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  Includes correspondence. with Giuseppe Lupis (Sottosegretario di Stato per gli Affari Esteri der Italiana).
- Land Tenure, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  Includes correspondence. with George Aiken (Senator), F. Bradford Morse, (Congressman Carlos Sanz de Santamaria (Inter- American Committee on the Alliance for Progress); William C. Doherty, Jr. (AIFLD) and Leveo V. Sanchez (Dept. of State) re land use and
- "M", 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  Includes correspondence. with George Meany re SR's retirement; summary of rights of workers suspended by Castro
- "N", 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  Includes correspondence. with Richard Nixon re SR's book
- "0" (Box 13, Folder 14)
  Corres. w/John O'Grady labor attach concerning Romualdi's trip to lecture in Colombia (1966)
- "P", 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  Routine correspondence. re SR's book
- "R", 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  Letters re SR's promotion of his book including an exchange of letters with Nelson Rockefeller and Victor Riesel
- "S" (Box 13, Folder 17)
- "T", 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  Letters re SR's work as a consultant for True Temper Corporation in labor and other negotiations with Industria Nacional de Implemetos Agricolas in Venezuela
- "u", 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  Largely correspondence. with William H. Hickey, President, the United Corp. re Latin-American affairs in general and work as a consultant to the United Corporations subsidiaries, the True Temper Corporation, Canadian International Power Co. Ltd. and the
- "V", 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  Includes correspondence. with Ramon Villeda Morales (June 22, August 19) re SR's book
- "W", 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  Laudatory letters from John Wasson and Robert Wholey (AIFLO) upon SR's retirement and an invitation from George L-P Weaver (US Asst. Secretary of Labor, International Affairs) for Romualdi and his wife to attend a luncheon in his honor (11/24/65)
- "The AFL-CIO: Philosophy and Structure -The Functions of National and Local Unions", 1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- "The Structure of the AFL-CIO", 1963-1964 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- "The Inter American Policy of the AFL" 2 lectures: 1) Defense of Freedom and Representative Democracy; 2) Economic Development and Living Standards, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- "Role of Free Trade-Unionism in the Alliance for Progress", 1965 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- "Outline of the Development of Union Movement in Chile" (Box 14, Folder 5)
- "Collective Bargaining in the United States, 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- "The struggle Against Communism in Latin America Labor", 1965 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- "Factors for Success in the Cooperative Enterprise", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- "The Function of Democratic Trade -Unionism in Modern Society", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- "The Role of Labor Education in Economic Development in a Modern Society" (Box 14, Folder 10)
- "Labor Union History" - US (See Also: US - Labor Union History) (Box 14, Folder 11)
- "General Considerations Concerning Unionism in the Americas" (Box 14, Folder 12)
- "Ideological Origins of the Latin American Labor Movement", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- "Characteristics of the Labor Movement in Latin America" (Box 14, Folder 14)
- "Necessities and Characteristics of the Labor Movement in Latin America", 1966 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- "Symposium on Latin America - Wellesley College - Problems of Economic and Social Development", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- "Law of Labor Management Relations" (Box 14, Folder 17)
- "ORIT and Labor Relations in Latin America", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 18)
- "History of the Development Union Movement. in Peru" (Box 14, Folder 19)
- "History of Unions" by Pablo Jaime Garzon, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 20)
- "The Relations of Unions With Governments and Political Parties" (Box 14, Folder 21)
- "The Function of Trade Unionism in Modern Society" (Box 14, Folder 22)
- "History of the United States Labor Movement - Economic and Social Theories" (Box 14, Folder 23)
- "The Functions of Trade Unions in The United States" (Box 14, Folder 24)
- "Short History of Union Movement in the United States", 1955 (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous notes. (Box 14, Folder 26)
- First Draft (Box 15)
- First Draft (Box 16)
- Second Draft (Box 17)
- Final Draft (Box 18)
- Nixon Clippings, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  Clippings concerning Nixon trip to Latin America
- Free Trade Union Committee, 1951-1954 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  Includes correspondence. with Jay Lovestone (Exec. Secretary) concerning John Fishburn and his activities; British Honduras General Workers' Union; Robert Alexander's trip to South America as reported by Arturo Jauegui (1952); ORIT and Turkish islands (19
- Information Kit for U.S. Delegation to Inauguration in Buenos Aires., 1958 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  Includes program for Richard and Pat Nixon and profiles on various leaders in Argentina (April 28 -May 4, 1958)
- Inter-American Trade Union Conference in Lima, Peru, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  Jan. 10, 1948: Includes correspondence. dealing with establishment of the Conference and its objectives
- AFL-CIO Tour of Latin-America, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Includes clippings and interview with Romualdi
- AFL-CIO Good Will Mission to Latin America, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  Includes correspondence. and reprints
- Romualdi visit to San Paulo, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  Includes clippings and photos of the trip
- Report of AFL Delegation to Havana Cuba, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  for the InterAmerican Conference for Democracy and Freedom.
- Photographs (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Condolences (to Mimi Romualdi), 1967 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Misc. notes and clippings (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Misc. clippings (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 21)